<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Travel on THE TIME OPTIMIST</title>
    <link>http://www.thetimeoptimist.com/categories/travel/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Travel on THE TIME OPTIMIST</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <atom:link href="http://www.thetimeoptimist.com/categories/travel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>On a Shoestring: 5 Budget Things to Do in NYC</title>
      <link>http://www.thetimeoptimist.com/post/budget-nyc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2017 15:06:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.thetimeoptimist.com/post/budget-nyc/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;A week in New York City doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to be expensive. Here&amp;rsquo;s a rundown of  free/cheap activities that I loved in the city that never sleeps - they&amp;rsquo;ll get you on your feet &lt;em&gt;and burning off all that amazing food you&amp;rsquo;re going to have there&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm3.staticflickr.com/2911/32421506584_fba0e35b30_b_d.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;alt text&#34; title=&#34;Sour cream doughnut and Korean slider&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;5-peruse-the-markets&#34;&gt;5. Peruse the Markets&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re going to be there during the weekend, head to Williamsburg for &lt;strong&gt;Artists &amp;amp; Fleas&lt;/strong&gt; for handmade gifts and &lt;strong&gt;Smorgasburg&lt;/strong&gt; for cuisine. While you&amp;rsquo;re in Williamsburg, &lt;strong&gt;Atlas Cafe&lt;/strong&gt; is on the corner of a street and is best for watching the world go by. Also try a doughnut from &lt;strong&gt;Peter Pan&amp;rsquo;s Bakery&lt;/strong&gt;, notably their sour cream one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm4.staticflickr.com/3938/32882070270_9bf465c5a0_b_d.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;alt text&#34; title=&#34;Japanese Hill-and-Pond Garden&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;4-relax-in-the-parks&#34;&gt;4. Relax in the Parks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My top picks are &lt;strong&gt;Brooklyn Botanical Gardens&lt;/strong&gt; (free on Tuesdays) and &lt;strong&gt;Washington Square Park&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Walking through BBG in the morning is the most serene way to start your day. There are different gardens to explore within, my favourites being the &lt;strong&gt;Shakespeare Garden&lt;/strong&gt; (housing 80+ plants featured in Shakespeare&amp;rsquo;s sonnets and plays) and the century-old &lt;strong&gt;Japanese Hill-and-Pond Garden&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Washington Square Park is very lively on a sunny day; full of students, families, and chess players. Get your caffiene fix from the nearby &lt;strong&gt;Third Rail Coffee&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm1.staticflickr.com/706/32421506974_67bcd90136_b_d.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;alt text&#34; title=&#34;View from Brooklyn Bridge&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;3-bridge-hop&#34;&gt;3. Bridge Hop&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If it&amp;rsquo;s sunny and you&amp;rsquo;re up for a walk with a view, walk a bridge or two. I&amp;rsquo;d do these in the morning and spend the rest of the day on the other end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Brooklyn Bridge&lt;/strong&gt; is everybody&amp;rsquo;s favourite but it&amp;rsquo;s too crowded. I prefer &lt;strong&gt;Williamsburg Bridge&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Queensboro Bridge&lt;/strong&gt;. They&amp;rsquo;re grungier but the views are decent and you don&amp;rsquo;t have to shuffle through tourists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm4.staticflickr.com/3778/32421507514_188bf685ae_b_d.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;alt text&#34; title=&#34;Inside the Metropolitan Museum of Art&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-explore-the-museums&#34;&gt;2. Explore the Museums&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My favourites are the &lt;strong&gt;Metropolitan Museum of Art&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Museum of Modern Art&lt;/strong&gt;: the Met is pay as you wish and MoMA is free on Fridays between 4-8pm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sadly, you cannot explore all of the Met in one day so I recommend doing 1 or 2 of their museum tours; the staff are all volunteers and they&amp;rsquo;re very passionate, insightful, and up for discussion about the art.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Head straight to floors 5 and 4 of MoMA for the good stuff from 1890- and don&amp;rsquo;t forget to pick up a free portable tour guide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm4.staticflickr.com/3802/32882071090_5ea2790afe_b_d.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;alt text&#34; title=&#34;View from the Staten Island ferry&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-take-in-the-skyline&#34;&gt;1. Take in the Skyline&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Staten Island ferry&lt;/strong&gt; is free and allows you to marvel the skyline - just make sure you stand at the south end of the ferry. Squint hard enough and you can spot Lady Liberty in the distance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You definitely need to go across the &lt;strong&gt;High Line&lt;/strong&gt;; old train tracks turned into a park/walkway above Greenwich Village. You get a view of Brooklyn on one side and Manhattan on the other. There are benches and chairs along it so it&amp;rsquo;s a great place to rest and people-watch on a bright afternoon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bonus: My first experience of the skyline was going up the observation deck at &lt;strong&gt;Rockefeller Centre&lt;/strong&gt; for $34. Not the most wallet-friendly but, unlike the Empire State Building, the sweeping views of the city are completely unobstructed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for the all kind words on my first post, I&amp;rsquo;ve got loads more Pocket Guides to write up so stay tuned. The Time Optimist was shortly on Instagram but will be on hiatus while I settle into with blogging - one step at a time!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pocket Guide: 3 Days in Amsterdam</title>
      <link>http://www.thetimeoptimist.com/post/amsterdam/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2017 14:39:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.thetimeoptimist.com/post/amsterdam/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm3.staticflickr.com/2937/32249529654_6f00324045_b_d.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;alt text&#34; title=&#34;Canal in Amsterdam&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm1.staticflickr.com/659/32280057763_40ed4323fd_b_d.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;alt text&#34; title=&#34;Book market in Spui&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm3.staticflickr.com/2431/32280078753_6b58fc4bf2_b_d.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;alt text&#34; title=&#34;Roofs and reading&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm3.staticflickr.com/2849/33053388386_227ff517e3_b_d.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;alt text&#34; title=&#34;Massive stroopwafel&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm3.staticflickr.com/2848/33095121135_1d84d06ed3_b_d.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;alt text&#34; title=&#34;Poffertjes to share&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm3.staticflickr.com/2151/32280078913_a0f494cbe1_b_d.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;alt text&#34; title=&#34;Fresh strawberries at Albert Cuyp market&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm3.staticflickr.com/2723/32249530044_96341d55d7_b_d.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;alt text&#34; title=&#34;Herring with onions and a side of pickles&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm3.staticflickr.com/2943/32712980350_10f40db2f8_b_d.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;alt text&#34; title=&#34;Views on views&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm1.staticflickr.com/728/32712980130_1b2ae41a85_b_d.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;alt text&#34; title=&#34;Bridges and bikes&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm3.staticflickr.com/2702/33095121865_ebf8143a76_b_d.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;alt text&#34; title=&#34;Morning inspiration&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm4.staticflickr.com/3714/32249530964_09c498626e_b_d.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;alt text&#34; title=&#34;Hanging shoes&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm3.staticflickr.com/2829/33095122265_0e468dd89e_b_d.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;alt text&#34; title=&#34;Greenery&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm3.staticflickr.com/2613/32712980480_6d55e90876_b_d.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;alt text&#34; title=&#34;Animal creeper&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm4.staticflickr.com/3673/32712980010_c17c492617_b_d.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;alt text&#34; title=&#34;Building appreciation&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm3.staticflickr.com/2649/33095122455_0d0e52022e_b_d.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;alt text&#34; title=&#34;Public House of Art&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Escaped to Amsterdam for a long weekend with the girls back in September 2016. Sunny, laid-back, and refreshingly green. Autumn had yet to arrive so our days were mostly spent outside - but I&amp;rsquo;ll definitely be back for some hardcore museum hopping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;center-i-class-icon-sleep-i-center&#34;&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;icon-sleep&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Airbnb&lt;/strong&gt; - Stayed in a sunny studio apartment in Bos en Lommer, by a canal and above a friendly bar which we ended up in 2 out 3 nights. It&amp;rsquo;s roughly 4 km from the city centre, a 20 minute Uber ride away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;center-i-class-icon-do-i-center&#34;&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;icon-do&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Free walking tour&lt;/strong&gt; - Walking tours are my favourite way to get acquainted with a new city. There are plenty of highly rated free walking tours in Amsterdam to choose from, we just happened to go with Sandemans. It was a 2.5 hour tour morning walk, covering everything from the narrowest house in Amsterdam to the best place to try raw herring - reportedly Haring &amp;amp; Zo, if you&amp;rsquo;re curious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Red Light District tour&lt;/strong&gt; - An alternative way to spend an evening, with Sandemans again but for 14 euros. Our guide was engaging throughout, walking us through how the district came to be and the stories of some of the working girls. One of my favourite tours to date.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;center-i-class-icon-see-i-center&#34;&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;icon-see&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Boekenmarkt op het Spui&lt;/strong&gt; - Breathed in that old book smell at this small book market in the heart of Spui.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Albert Cuypmarkt&lt;/strong&gt; - Headed straight to this bustling market first thing on a Saturday morning and filled our stomachs on &lt;em&gt;poffertjes&lt;/em&gt; (little dutch pancakes) doused in syrup, huge &lt;em&gt;stroopwafels&lt;/em&gt; (thin waffles sandwiched between caramel) hot off the press, and raw herring topped with onions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bloemenmarkt&lt;/strong&gt; - Ambled through this famous flower market floating on water. Good place to pick up presents for the green-fingers in your life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Public House of Art&lt;/strong&gt; - Stumbled upon this friendly gallery with quirky pieces and ample seating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;center-i-class-icon-eat-i-center&#34;&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;icon-eat&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Het Warenhuis&lt;/strong&gt; - Stopped here for a tea break. Bright space with one side made up entirely of glass, made for people-watching.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cannibale Royale&lt;/strong&gt; - Cooked dinner back at the apartment for most nights but ventured out to this hip steak and burger joint on our last one. Dark, buzzing, perfect for groups. I had their signature, Le Cannibale Royale. For the record, sauerkraut goes great in a burger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;center-i-class-icon-night-i-center&#34;&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;icon-night&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bitterzoet&lt;/strong&gt; - Good Friday night at this intimate club; twenty-something crowd, decent music, and (on the night we went) free pizza thrown out to the masses.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>